Well, let me give you a massive welcome to the definitive A.I. Coder course.
This is the missing manual.
Over the course of three weeks, I'm going to take you on this extraordinary
journey that will end up with you being an expert at a Gentic engineering.
But first, a word of caution.
You need to buckle up.
You need to strap in because I have a wild ride in store for you.
This is going to be a rollercoaster.
I have so much to show you.
Let me tell you all about it.
It is standard fare with these kinds of courses.
A good way to go about doing it is to begin with the objectives, introduce myself, give
you the curriculum and the logistics.
Except I don't do that.
If you've been on any of my courses before, you know perfectly well that I always like
to start with instant gratification. Let's roll up sleeves, let's
build something together, there'll be plenty of time to come back later and do all of that stuff.
In the next three weeks, we're going to be working with a number of different AI products
that generate code, but for today, we're going to start with cursor, super popular, very easy to
use, and it has a free trial if you haven't used it before. So that's what we're going to use.
If you've used cursor before and you've
spent all of the free trial and you don't want to use it anymore, you don't need to.
You can just watch what I do right now or you can follow along with another product if you like.
We're just going to do something super simple because we want to use an AI to generate code
right away and then we'll get on with the course. Let's go do it.
And so the first thing to do is to bring up a browser. I'm in Chrome right here and I'm going to cursor.com cursor CUR SOR dot com press enter and here
we are. We are in cursors website. It says it's built to make you extraordinarily productive.
CURSA is the best way to code with AI. Well, we'll be the judge of that. We'll be using a
few of these and we can decide ourselves. But for now we are going to use CURa. So the first thing to do is to download it
and install it locally, which we will do now.
And it's worth keeping an eye on the course resources,
which will be linked in the platform.
To make sure that nothing's changed,
there's no extra instructions as you go,
but it should be pretty simple.
You start by going to download,
and you can download the right version for your platform.
For me, I'm on a Mac, an ARM Mac, an M1 Mac,
but you might pick Mac, Windows,
Ort Linux, and actually on the landing page, probably the button right here is allowing you
immediately to download the versions for your platform. So download that file, I'll press it now
to download from Mac, and then you will launch it on your computer once it's downloaded.
And just for the PC people to show you, here I am in a Microsoft Edge browser. I've gone to
cursor.com and download for Windows
is the default button,
which I'm pressing right now to,
and that's now downloading for the PC as well.
And so then on Windows once it's downloaded,
you open the file, the usual stuff,
you say you accept the agreement, you press next,
and then you just pick the normal defaults,
including that last one in particular add to path
is important, and then next,
and then install and then install
and cursor will be installed on your PC on a Mac. You just drag the box over to applications
and you're done. And when that's done, we will then get started with cursor.
And the first time you come into cursor, you should be prompted to sign in or sign up.
And of course, you're going to want to sign up if you don't already have a cursor
account, which should be free for the first few weeks, which is all that we need it for. And if you get this screen,
you can just press the sign in button there.
Or if you don't see this screen,
you should be able to go to the file menu
and say new menu, new window,
and then you will see the screen.
And then you press the sign in button.
It brings up a cursor window in the browser,
like this, sign in to cursor, continue to sign in.
And then you can say, don't have an account sign up and this is the screen
where you then enter your details, answer a few questions and then you will
have an account with cursor that you can sign into. As I say it should be there
of a trial period, should be free for a couple of weeks which is all that we
need to give it a good test run if you already have a cursor account so much
the better. Okay I will see you over in cursor if you have any problems with
this. Do look at the course resources or shoot me a question so I can help you out.
Okay, so then when you launch cursor, this is what you see. You see the cursor screen.
If you don't see exactly this screen, go to the file menu and choose new window and then this
is what you'll get. It may not say pro here. If you don't have a pro account, if you're on the free
trial account. And if you see login here you press that login again,
any problems message me. All right, the first thing we're going to do is open a project and I'm
going to show you what it looks like on a Mac and then on a PC. So cursor is based on VS code
and you may be very familiar with this already if you use VS code but open a project really means
I want to select a directory on my computer that directory will be used to house everything related to this
project. And it's typical for people to start in their home directory, mine is called ed, and then
to go to a folder called projects where you have your own projects. And if you don't have such a
folder, you press new folder to create projects. But I do have such a folder here it is. And here
I've got lots of projects. Here are all my projects. And what I can do now is press new folder and I can
type out instant for the name of this instant project and press create and here I am inside
instant and then I press open and it opens the project called instant and you'll tell that because
it says instant in block capitals right there. Okay, now let me show you the same thing on a PC.
So here I am on cursor and the PC. If it says sign in right there, I can click
there to go through and sign into cursor. Otherwise I can press open project. It comes
up. This is the kind of browser on a PC. I'm in my home folder again, add, I can create
a new folder or I can go into projects that already exist. That's how you create a new
folder. I'll go into projects and I can create a new folder, I can call it instant. And there is instant, I can go into instant
and then say select folder.
And here we are, we are now inside instant.
You can see it says instant on the top left,
that means we've got it right.
And this is the beginning of cursor on a PC.
Okay, so just orienting you on cursor.
We're seeing like three panes here on the left.
This is showing the whole file system of our project of instant and it's very empty
We don't have many files here right now
We will do very soon in the middle here is the main place where we'll see code and on the right
This is where we chat with an agent and if you're not seeing these three pains
Then there's various if you go to the view menu
There's an appearance sub-menu and you can toggle around different things until you do see these two
panes. I'm sure you'll figure it out, otherwise message me. Okay, what we're now going to do is
explore using the thing on the right, the agent, to actually do some work for us for the first time.
Now, look, something that I feel very strongly about, which I have on all of my courses,
is that when we build projects together, and I like building projects together, when we do it, I like them to have real world
commercial impact.
I like to build things which are actually valuable,
which perhaps you could think of monetizing at some point,
or users like a springboard for something else
that you want to build.
So for me being a business relevant,
business first is super important,
and invariably I like my projects to have business impact but but not today.
Today is going to be an exception, the only exception. Every one of the projects we do on
this course are going to have important business impact except for this one. Today we're just
going to have some fun because what better way to start than with something a bit entertaining.
So we're going to start with a fun project,
but don't worry if you're more all business,
it's going to be all business after this point.
Okay, let me show this to you.
When we click on the right over here,
we can talk to an LLM,
we can talk to a language model,
to an agent and have it do some work for us.
And if you're wondering what all of these things are,
don't worry, tomorrow I'm going to go through a
lot of the constructs agents, how they work, what they do and so on. And if you know all this
already well then you've seen this before but we're just going to have some fun it's going to
build from here. Okay, so what we put in here is going to be a message to our coding agent like
our sidekick that's going to work with us on this. And just below here we can choose what model
are we going to use, what AI is going to sit behind this
and work on it for us.
And depending on your plan, you might not be allowed to choose.
It might be set to auto, which means cursor gets to choose.
But on the plan that I'm on, I can actually choose and I have chosen GPT 5.2 codecs,
one of the strongest models that there are as of today.
So that's the one that we will use for now. And in here I'm going to put the
request that I have for this AI to work with me. Okay, and this is the request. Please build a
website for a 3D first person shooter game in an arena against one computer opponent controlled
by arrow keys and space barter shoot. All right, I'm sending that off and so should you. And off it goes doing stuff.
You can see the actions it's taken written here.
It's planning the next moves.
It's listed, it's exploring.
And off it goes doing stuff.
And it's writing a file.
A file just got written, called index.hml, or it's in the middle of writing it.
Now it's possible that it's going to ask you for permission to do various things,
in which case as long
as you're happy with it, you should say yes.
But it may well not like mine.
It depends on your settings, but I think I believe the default will be the same as me,
and it would just go off and do this stuff.
Creating files, writing stuff, and I am using GPT 5.2 codecs, and you might be using
a different model.
And the thing is, and something that you'll get familiar with on this course, is that
every one of
us will have a different experience. There is some uncertainty here that it is not necessarily
predictable what happens next, but this agent is off, it's doing stuff and it's working
on index.html.